Now that was when we had two classes namely receiving a gift or not receiving a gift.
前面说的是有两个类别 即收到礼物和没有收到礼物
What happens if we have more classes? Let's take a look.
如果有多个类别呢？我们来看看
So, we have a similar problem.
问题差不多
We still have three doors and this problem is still not the Monty Hall problem.
依然有三道门 并且不是蒙提霍尔问题
Behind each door there can be an animal and the animal can be of three types;
每道门后面有一个动物 动物可以是三种类型
it can be a duck,
可以是鸭子
it can be a beaver,
海狸
or it can be a walrus.
或海象
So, let's look at this table of probabilities.
我们看看这个概率表格
According to the first column in the table,
根据表格中的第一列
behind the first door,
在第一道门后面
the probability of finding a duck is 0.7,
发现是鸭子的概率是 0.7
the probability of finding a beaver is 0.2 and the probability finding a walrus is 0.1.
发现是海狸的概率是 0.2 发现是海象的概率是 0.1
Notice that the numbers in each column need to add (up) to
注意 每列的数字之和需为 1
1 because there is some animal behind door 1.
因为第一道门后面会有个动物
The numbers in the rows do not need to add (up) to 1 as you can see.
可以看出 一行的数字不一定加起来是 1
It could easily be that we have a duck behind every door and that's okay.
很有可能每道门后面都有一只鸭子 这样是可以的
So, let's look at a sample scenario.
我们来看一个示例情形
Let's say we have our three doors and behind the first door, there's a duck;
假设有三道门 第一道门后面有一只鸭子
behind the second door, there's a walrus;
第二道门后面有一头海狸
and behind the third door,
第三道门后面
there's also a walrus.
有一头海象
Recall that the probabilities are given by the table.
回忆下表格中的概率
So, a duck behind the first door is 0.7 likely,
第一道门后面是鸭子的概率是 0.7
a walrus behind the second door is 0.3
第二道门后面是海象的概率是 0.3
likely and a walrus behind the third door is 0.4 likely.
第三道门后面是海象的概率是 0.4
So, the probability of obtaining these three animals is
获得这三种动物的概率是
the product of the probabilities of the three events,
这三个事件的概率积
since they are independent events,
因为它们是独立事件
which in this case, it's 0.084.
这里是 0.084
And as we learn, the cross-entropy here is
我们知道 交叉熵是
given by the sums of the negatives of the logarithms of the probabilities.
概率对数负值的和
So the first one is negative logarithm 0.7.
第一个是 -ln(0.7)
The second one is negative logarithm 0.3,
第二个是 -ln(0.3)
and the third one is negative logarithm of 0.4.
第三个是 -ln(0.4)
The cross-entropies and the sum of these three,
交叉熵 即三者之和
which is actually 2.48.
是 2.48.
But we want a formula, so let's put some variables here.
但是我们希望得出公式 所以设定一些变量
So, P11 is the probability of finding a duck behind door one;
P11 表示在第一道门后面发现鸭子的概率
P12 is the probability of finding a duck behind door two, etc.
P12 表示在第二道门后面发现鸭子的概率 等等
And let's have the indicator variables: y1j be 1 if there's a duck
那么我们可以得出：如果第 j 道门后面有鸭子 则 y1j 为 1
behind door j. y2j be 1 if there's a beaver behind door j;
如果第 j 道门后面有一头海狸 则 y2j 为 1
and y3j be 1 if there is a walrus behind door j.
如果第 j 道门后面有一头海象 则 y3j 为 1
And these variables are zero otherwise.
否则这些变量是 0
And so, the formula for the cross-entropy is simply the
交叉熵的公式就变成
negative of the summation from i= 1 to n,
从 i= 1 到 n 的和
up to summation from y = j to m of y_i_j times the logarithm of p_i_j.
从 y = j 到 m 的和 yij 乘以 ln(pij)
In this case, n is the number of classes.
这里 n 表示类别数量
This formula works because the y_i_j being 01 made sure that we're
这个公式可行 是因为 Yij 要么为 0 要么为 1
only adding the logarithms of
以此确保我们仅加上
the probabilities of the events that actually have occurred.
实际发生的事件的概率对数
And voila. This is the formula for the cross-entropy in more classes.
这就是更多类别的交叉熵
Now, I'm going to leave you with a question: given that we have a formula for
现在问一个问题：我们得出了两个类别的交叉熵
cross-entropy for two classes and one for m classes,
以及 m 个类别的交叉熵
these formulas look different but are they the same for m=2?
这两个公式看起来不一样 如果 m=2 它俩一样吗？
Obviously, the answer is yes,
很明显答案是肯定的
but it's a cool exercise to actually write them down and
但是可以练习下 写下公式
convince yourself that they are actually the same.
并自己证明它们是一样的